# Ivan Poliakov

# LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Email: ivan.polyakov.01@gmail.com

Mobile: +31 627 21 72 51

Location: Maastricht, Limburg, The Netherlands

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a machine learning engineer specializing in Deep Learning, Generative AI, algorithmic optimization and mathematics, primarily writing code in C++, Python and C. I have 1 year of work experience in AI industry and am currently working on several ongoing research projects as a part of my MSc degree in AI at Maastricht University while seeking new job opportunities.



#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Domain Knowledge** : Algorithm design and optimization, Deep Learning, Generative AI,

LLMs and Agents, NLP, Computer Vision,

Probability and Mathematical Optimization, Multithreading

**Programming Languages**: C++, Python, C, Java

**Machine Learning** : PyTorch, NumPy, SciPy, scikit-learn, LangChain

**Development** : C++ STL, REST API, Flask, Django, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, PyQt, React.js

: Google Cloud Platform, Git, Linux, Docker, CMake, gradle, Google Test, Bash **Platforms & Tools** 

**Data & Visualization** : pandas, OpenCV, Matplotlib, seaborn

### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

**ML** engineer Sep 2024 - Jan 2024

Stealth Startups Remote - USA

Building product prototypes that revolve around data mining, agentic workflows and latest AI research.

#### **NLP Engineer (internship)**

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Garant Remote - Moscow, Russia

- Built a minimalistic library for working with common text processing techniques.
- Designed a Q&A model for a set of common user queries.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Maastricht University**

**Maastricht University** 

Maastricht, Limburg, The Netherlands

Master of Artificial Intelligence – ongoing research

Feb 2024 - present

Maastricht, Limburg, The Netherlands

Bachelor of Data Science and Artificial Intelligence – thesis on GANs

2019-2022

## **PROJECTS AND ACTIVITIES**

Mini-renderer C++Repository

• Developed a 3D renderer with zero dependencies in C++, supporting camera view, lighting, and shading techniques.

• Can render a 2500-face model on a standard ThinkPad CPU.

**Tetris with Autoplay** Repository

• Implemented a Tetris game powered by a genetic algorithm for auto-play.

**Juice Pong Robot** Python, YOLO Repository

• Built a robotic setup for "juice pong" using lab components and a 3D-printed spoon, integrating YOLO for object tracking.

#### **Competitive Programming**

C++, Python, stress-testing

Codeforces profile

- Qualified for the Russian Olympiad in Informatics national finals in 2019.
- · Achieved Master rank on Codeforces in 2021 and founded the first team from my university to compete at ICPC NWERC in 2024.
- · Coached dozens of students one-on-one and in group settings.